# Vinod Sridhar Dalavai

585-710-1636 • Rochester, NY • vd1605@rit.edu • https://dsvinod90.github.io/dsvinod90

#### **PROFILE**

Seeking an internship/cooperative position to work on the design and development of high-quality software systems. Looking to work with an enthusiastic team of engineers, bringing to the table over 4 years of software engineering experience, strong technical skills, and an ability to climb steep learning curves effectively. **Areas of Interest:** Distributed systems, computer networks, systems application development, software engineering. **Core Skills Include:** Java, Python, Ruby, Javascript, MySQL, Unix, Spring Boot, NodeJS, Rails, CSS, HTML5, Product/system ownership, Data Structures and Algorithms, Object oriented design, API Design

#### **EDUCATION**

**Rochester Institute of Technology** | Master of Science in Computer Science Rochester, New York.

Expected - May 2023

- Related coursework: Distributed Systems, Computer Networks, Advanced Object-Oriented Programming, and Foundations of Algorithms.
- **Highlights:** Received praise for a <u>presentation about Resilient Distributed Datasets(RDDs)</u> for the distributed systems class. Exploring research opportunities/projects in the field with Professor. Mustafa Rafique.

**Siddaganga Institute of Technology** | Bachelor of Technology in Chemical Engineering Tumkur, India.

2008 - 2012

# **PROJECTS**

Open Source - ory/keto.

Feb 2022 - Apr 2022

Overview: Implemented a <u>hybrid logical clock</u> for providing consistency guarantees across distributed nodes.

**Responsibilities**: • Using *PostgresSQL*, *Redis*, and *GoLang* to implement the hybrid logical clock (HLC) for synchronization in a distributed architecture. • Modify the API responses to accommodate the newly developed HLC timestamps and test extensively with cURL and Postman.

## Lunar Rover - Network Protocol Development.

Feb 2022 - April 2022

**Overview**: Developed the *RIPv2* protocol and a reliable data transfer protocol from scratch using *Java Socket programming*.

**Responsibilities**: • Designed the *RIPv2* message (packet) header. • Created and updated the routing tables for an arbitrary number of routers using the *Bellman-Ford* shortest path algorithm. • Simulated the network using multicast IP and used *Docker* to test and iteratively develop the protocol. • Also developed and implemented the transport layer protocol similar to the *TCP/IP protocol*.

# Scripbox.com - Payment Gateway Integration

Sept 2018 - Dec 2018

**Overview**: Integrated third-party payment gateways for Scripbox.com's investment platform handling over 30K payments daily.

**Responsibilities**: • Used *Ruby on Rails* to develop the APIs to allow all forms of online payments. • With a focus on security, wrote an extensive test suite using *RSpec* for unit testing. • Performed API tests with *Postman* and followed best practices concerning web and API development. • Collaborated with external developers from various financial institutions and undertook independent responsibilities to meet business requirements.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Software Engineer - Platforms.

Dec 2016 - May 2021

Scripbox.com Pvt. Ltd. | Bangalore, India.

- Designed, developed, and maintained web services for customer-facing investment platforms as well as the internal CRM tools.
- Ideated the need for an automation suite and developed the system for performing automated regression testing (using *Capybara* and *Rspei*) in *Gitlab CI*. All subsequent production deployments were contingent on this suite passing.
- Proactively involved in triaging and fixing high-priority, high-impact bugs with a short turnaround time.
- Undertook DevOps responsibilities as the need arose by analyzing system resource utilization using *Grafana* and followed the team-defined protocols in place to resolve errors.
- Reported to scrum manager every week and implemented robust software engineering principles to participate in the full software development life-cycle of internal tools.
- Involved in Sprint Planning Meetings to identify functional requirements, convert them into engineering tasks and estimate timelines for delivery

## Systems Engineer - British Petroleum/Aviva

Jan 2013 - Dec 2016

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd | India/UK

- Prepared and executed regression test scenarios and test cases of clients' web applications.
- Designed, developed, and executed performance scripts using HP Loadrunner and analyzed test results.
- Logged test artifacts and results in *IIRA*.